export default {
  id: 'mid_5b',
  name: '상용한자(중학5/한자찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '독:えり/음:きん', answer: ['襟'] },
    { question: '독:こよみ/음:れき', answer: ['暦'] },
    { question: '독:답답할, 울창할/음:うつ', answer: ['鬱'] },
    { question: '독:あさ/음:ま', answer: ['麻'] },
    { question: '독:문지를, 어루만질/음:ま', answer: ['摩'] },
    { question: '독:みが(く)/음:ま', answer: ['磨'] },
    { question: '독:마귀/음:ま', answer: ['魔'] },
    { question: '독:붉을/음:しゅ', answer: ['朱'] },
    { question: '독:구슬, 진주/음:しゅ', answer: ['珠'] },
    { question: '독:こと/음:しゅ', answer: ['殊'] },
    { question: '독:결혼할/음:こん', answer: ['婚'] },
    { question: '독:막을, 당할/음:てい', answer: ['抵'] },
    { question: '독:큰 집/음:てい', answer: ['邸'] },
    { question: '독:か、かお(り)、かお(る)/음:こう、[きょう]', answer: ['香'] },
    { question: '독:일컬을/음:しょう', answer: ['称'] },
    { question: '독:うれ(える)、うれ(い)/음:しゅう', answer: ['愁'] },
    { question: '독:な(える)/음:い', answer: ['萎'] },
    { question: '독:なし/음:', answer: ['梨'] },
    { question: '독:이질/음:り', answer: ['痢'] },
    { question: '독:およ(ぶ)、およ(び)、およ(ぼす)/음:きゅう', answer: ['及'] },
    { question: '독:あつか(う)/음:', answer: ['扱'] },
    { question: '독:ひい(でる)/음:しゅう', answer: ['秀'] },
    { question: '독:す(く)、す(かす)、す(ける)/음:とう', answer: ['透'] },
    { question: '독:さそ(う)/음:ゆう', answer: ['誘'] },
    { question: '독:가지런할/음:せい', answer: ['斉'] },
    { question: '독:약지을/음:ざい', answer: ['剤'] },
    { question: '독:재계할/음:さい', answer: ['斎'] },
    { question: '독:なぞ/음:', answer: ['謎'] },
    { question: '독:국화/음:きく', answer: ['菊'] },
    { question: '독:단장할/음:しょう', answer: ['粧'] },
    { question: '독:つ(ぐ)/음:けい', answer: ['継'] },
    { question: '독:おく/음:おう', answer: ['奥'] },
    { question: '독:ゆ(れる)、ゆ(る)、ゆ(らぐ)、ゆ(るぐ)、ゆ(する)、ゆ(さぶる)、ゆ(すぶる)/음:よう', answer: ['揺'] },
    { question: '독:うたい, うた(う)/음:よう', answer: ['謡'] },
    { question: '독:ひるがえ(る)、ひるがえ(す)/음:ほん', answer: ['翻'] },
    { question: '독:울타리/음:はん', answer: ['藩'] },
    { question: '독:살필/음:しん', answer: ['審'] },
    { question: '독:ふ(く)、ぬぐ(う)/음:しょく', answer: ['拭'] },
    { question: '독:세금거둘, 줄/음:ふ', answer: ['賦'] },
    { question: '독:ふくろ/음:たい', answer: ['袋'] },
    { question: '독:칠/음:ばつ', answer: ['伐'] },
    { question: '독:문벌/음:ばつ', answer: ['閥'] },
    { question: '독:사다리, 잔도/음:さん', answer: ['桟'] },
    { question: '독:밟을, 행할/음:せん', answer: ['践'] },
    { question: '독:쪽지, 주석/음:せん', answer: ['箋'] },
    { question: '독:まどう/음:わく', answer: ['惑'] },
    { question: '독:굶주릴/음:が', answer: ['餓'] },
    { question: '독:거동, 법도/음:ぎ', answer: ['儀'] },
    { question: '독:희생/음:ぎ', answer: ['犠'] },
    { question: '독:심을, 기를/음:さい', answer: ['栽'] },
    { question: '독:の(せる)、の(る)/음:さい', answer: ['載'] },
    { question: '독:받들, 일/음:たい', answer: ['戴'] },
    { question: '독:가늘/음:せん', answer: ['繊'] },
    { question: '독:도둑/음:ぞく', answer: ['賊'] },
    { question: '독:しげ(る)/음:も', answer: ['茂'] },
    { question: '독:친척/음:せき', answer: ['戚'] },
    { question: '독:さげす(む)/음:べつ', answer: ['蔑'] },
    { question: '독:위엄/음:い', answer: ['威'] },
    { question: '독:해, 세월/음:さい、[せい]', answer: ['歳'] },
    { question: '독:ほろ(びる)、ほろ(ぼす)/음:めつ', answer: ['滅'] },
    { question: '독:한탄할, 섭섭할/음:かん', answer: ['憾'] },
    { question: '독:세찰, 매울/음:れつ', answer: ['烈'] },
    { question: '독:さ(く)、さ(ける)/음:れつ', answer: ['裂'] },
    { question: '독:ほうむ(る)/음:そう', answer: ['葬'] },
    { question: '독:ふ(える)、ふ(やす)/음:しょく', answer: ['殖'] },
    { question: '독:いの(る)/음:き', answer: ['祈'] },
    { question: '독:쪼갤/음:せき', answer: ['析'] },
    { question: '독:장인/음:しょう', answer: ['匠'] },
    { question: '독:き(る)/음:ざん', answer: ['斬'] },
    { question: '독:점점/음:ぜん', answer: ['漸'] },
    { question: '독:잠깐/음:ざん', answer: ['暫'] },
    { question: '독:おか/음:きゅう', answer: ['丘'] },
    { question: '독:たけ/음:がく', answer: ['岳'] },
    { question: '독:はま/음:ひん', answer: ['浜'] },
    { question: '독:밝을/음:てつ', answer: ['哲'] },
    { question: '독:ちか(う)/음:せい', answer: ['誓'] },
    { question: '독:ゆ(く)、い(く)/음:せい', answer: ['逝'] },
    { question: '독:たきぎ/음:しん', answer: ['薪'] },
    { question: '독:물리칠/음:せき', answer: ['斥'] },
    { question: '독:うった(える)/음:そ', answer: ['訴'] },
    { question: '독:きわ(める)、きわ(まる)/음:きゅう', answer: ['窮'] },
    { question: '독:とむら(う)/음:ちょう', answer: ['弔'] },
    { question: '독:おぼ(れる)/음:でき', answer: ['溺'] },
    { question: '독:はら(う)/음:ふつ', answer: ['払'] },
    { question: '독:わ(く)、わ(かす)/음:ふつ', answer: ['沸'] },
    { question: '독:마칠/음:りょう', answer: ['了'] },
    { question: '독:구멍, 공자/음:こう', answer: ['孔'] },
    { question: '독:날랠, 사나울/음:もう', answer: ['猛'] },
    { question: '독:ほこ/음:む', answer: ['矛'] },
    { question: '독:やわら(か)、やわら(かい)/음:じゅう、にゅう', answer: ['柔'] },
    { question: '독:きも/음:かん', answer: ['肝'] },
    { question: '독:あせ/음:かん', answer: ['汗'] },
    { question: '독:のき/음:けん', answer: ['軒'] },
    { question: '독:あわ(せる)/음:へい', answer: ['併'] },
    { question: '독:병/음:びん', answer: ['瓶'] },
    { question: '독:もち/음:へい', answer: ['餅'] },
    { question: '독:담/음:へい', answer: ['塀'] }
  ]
}
